Muhammed Esat Ozen

Software Developer
Winchester, MA
(203) 278-6572
ozenesat@gmail.com
Portfolio, GitHub, LinkedIn
(Authorized to work in the US for any employer)

Skills

JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Next.js, Node.js, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose, MongoDB, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, Postman, Git/GitHub/Gitlab, Arcanist, Phabricator, Express, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Material-UI, REST, Linux/Ubuntu, Agile/Scrum.

Experience

MAY 2020 - PRESENT

Rapic.io, Seattle, WA - Front-end Developer

- Designed, implemented and tested the application from scratch with Next.Js & React.
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 authorization to access Google APIs into the React app with JWT and back-end server. Integrated YouTube, API for the live stream and live chat.
- Built and consumed Restful APIs in coordination with 3rd Party APIs & backend.
- Working remotely with 6 developers over GitHub with Agile/Scrum methodology.

FEB 2020 - MAY 2020

General Assembly, Boston, MA - Software Engineer Fellow

- Completed 12 weeks/500+ hours of intensive Full Stack Development instruction.
- Built client-side applications with responsive behavior using React with third-party APIs.
- Developed 4 full-stack web applications in four days sprints independently and collaboratively while practicing Agile methodology. Utilized Git for version control.
- Built RESTful APIs to store data for web-apps using Rails & SQL or Node.js & MongoDB.

Featured Projects

- <u>Photo Collector</u>: React application with Google Authentication and Unsplash API.
 {React, Node, Express, MongoDB, JS, OAuth} <u>Front-End Repo</u> <u>Back-End Repo</u>.
- <u>Survey Say</u>: Full-stack, team project for single page online survey application.
 {React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose} <u>Front-End Repo</u> <u>Back-End Repo</u>.
- <u>The Lists</u>: Single page to-do list application with Handlebars and Bootstrap techs. {AJAX, jQuery, JS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL} <u>Front-End Repo</u> <u>Back-End Repo</u>
- QMic.online: Start-up project which allows live broadcasts to get online guests with 'n to 1' communication principle. {React, Redux, Python, PostgreSQL, OAuth, REST}

MAY 2019 - FEB 2020

Ace It Education, Boston, MA - Web Developer

- Built and maintained two websites for the company's DBAs with WordPress.
- Managed e-mail accounts with G-Suite and e-mail campaigns with MailChimp.
- Provided technical support for the weekly events and classes of the company.
- Created social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite.

MAY 2018 - MAY 2019

The Fix, Farmington, CT - *Project Manager*

- Efficiently managed a yearly budget of ~\$1 million and increased the profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services tailored to customer needs.

Education

Middle East Technical University- Bachelor of Science, Mathematics

Abstract Algebra, Combinatorics, Cryptography, Discrete Mathematics, Intro. to C, Number Theory *Honors;* Proudly served & elected as President of the Student Council for two years.

Summary

With a quantitative academic background and startup experience, able to master new skills quickly. Enjoys breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking in transferring innovative ideas into the codebase. Experienced in diverse work areas in three different countries as a highly adaptive world citizen.